<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title><![CDATA[timbroder.com]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.timbroder.com/blog/tags/autocomplete.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="https://www.timbroder.com/"/>
    <updated>2018-09-09T12:21:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.timbroder.com/</id>
            <author>
            <name><![CDATA[Tim Broder]]></name>            <email><![CDATA[timothy.broder@gmail.com]]></email>        </author>
        <generator uri="http://sculpin.io/">Sculpin</generator>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google goes Instant]]></title>
            <link href="https://www.timbroder.com/2010/09/google-goes-instant.html"/>
            <updated>2010-09-08T19:21:05+00:00</updated>
            <id>https://www.timbroder.com/2010/09/google-goes-instant.html</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Instant is a new search enhancement that shows results as you type. We
are pushing the limits of our technology and infrastructure to help you get
better search results, faster. Our key technical insight was that people type
slowly, but read quickly, typically taking 300 milliseconds between
keystrokes, but only 30 milliseconds (a tenth of the time!) to glance at
another part of the page. This means that you can scan a results page while
you type. The most obvious change is that you get to the right content much
faster than before because you don’t have to finish typing your full search
term, or even press “search.” Another shift is that seeing results as you type
helps you formulate a better search term by providing instant feedback. You
can now adapt your search on the fly until the results match exactly what you
want. In time, we may wonder how search ever worked in any other way.</p>

<h2 id="benefits">Benefits</h2>

<p><strong>Faster Searches:</strong> By predicting your search and showing results before you finish typing, Google Instant can save 2-5 seconds per search.</p>

<p><strong>Smarter Predictions:</strong> Even when you don’t know exactly what you’re looking for, predictions help guide your search. The top prediction is shown in grey text directly in the search box, so you can stop typing as soon as you see what you need.</p>

<p><strong>Instant Results:</strong> Start typing and results appear right before your eyes. Until now, you had to type a full search term, hit return, and hope for the right results. Now results appear instantly as you type, helping you see where you’re headed, every step of the way.</p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
    </feed>