<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title><![CDATA[timbroder.com]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.timbroder.com/blog/tags/coffee.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="https://www.timbroder.com/"/>
    <updated>2018-09-09T12:21:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.timbroder.com/</id>
            <author>
            <name><![CDATA[Tim Broder]]></name>            <email><![CDATA[timothy.broder@gmail.com]]></email>        </author>
        <generator uri="http://sculpin.io/">Sculpin</generator>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fussy Coffee]]></title>
            <link href="https://www.timbroder.com/2015/07/fussy-coffee.html"/>
            <updated>2015-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
            <id>https://www.timbroder.com/2015/07/fussy-coffee.html</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the years I've <a href="http://www.marco.org/2010/06/16/the-coffee-setup-2010-i-own-a-lot-of-ways-to" title="read">read</a> or <a href="http://techdistortion.com/podcasts/pragmatic/episode-30-coffee" title="listened">listened</a> to some of the <a href="http://www.caseyliss.com/2014/7/25/neat-ice-kit" title="fussy">fussy</a> drinking <a href="https://david-smith.org/blog/2014/05/22/my-travel-coffee-kit/" title="habbits">habbits</a> of people I respect and follow.  I've been meaning to write about what I do for coffee for a while. A <a href="https://twitter.com/jessicalippke" title="coworker">coworker</a> of mine has asked and a recent post by my friend <a href="http://www.samuelstrickland.me/blog/2015/7/coffee-nerdery" title="Sam">Sam</a> kicked me to sit down and write it.</p>

<p>Sam talks about Coffee Nerdery and it made me stop and think about how much I get into it. When I was younger, "nerd" had a negative connotation. I learned to not let it bother me a long time ago. <a href="http://fishingboatproceeds.tumblr.com/post/31143873695/now-available-for-pre-order-at-dftba-com-in" title="Nerds are passionate about many things">Nerds are passionate about many things</a>. For me it was comics, computers, books. Now, add a liiiitle bit of coffee into that.</p>

<p>Don't get me wrong, <a href="http://www.marco.org/2014/03/31/throwing-k-cups-in-glass-houses" title="regular coffee is just fine">regular coffee is just fine</a>. Half the time, at work, I just have a cup from the pot. (Granted, that's <a href="http://gorillacoffee.com/" title="good coffee">good coffee</a>). But, as I've written about previously, <a href="http://timbroder.com/2014/09/morning-rituals.html" title="rituals are important">rituals are important</a>. Some of what I do with coffee is for the taste. Some of it is the ritual of preparing it and the comfort that it brings. Some of it is feeling included in a club, even if that club exists only online in the form of twitter, slack, and blog posts. Because of a few of the gadgets I use, I thought I was a little nerdier. But, the gadgets is where it ends. I don't fiddle with temperature or what I use to stir. I just get good beans and prep them with what I have.</p>

<p>At the end of the day it doesn't matter. If you are passionate about something, want to throw all of your energy into it, are just curious, or just want to fiddle. Do it. If it entertains you, it scratches an itch, or you get something else out of it. Do it. Nerdism is starting to feel like a post within itself. Back to coffee.</p>

<p>Here's what I do:
I start up the kettle. When it hisses, I pour it in
<img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/523/19799533225_f86f5625d2_z_d.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The beans I use are usually from the <a href="https://bluebottlecoffee.com/f4a9df89" title="Blue Bottle Coffee mail service">Blue Bottle Coffee mail service</a>. (&lt;-- referral link. help me out!) I'll do a review of the service at some point in the future. For now, check out <a href="http://www.marco.org/2012/05/29/tonx-coffee" title="Marco's">Marco's</a>
<img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/452/19178658403_356e1f2eeb_z_d.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>I grind the beans by hand using a <a href="http://amzn.to/1Mefklf" title="hand">Porlex JP-30 Stainless Steel Coffee Grinder</a></p>

<p><img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3732/19611530590_717563e7a2_z_d.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/560/19773361246_66d5776853_z_d.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Next is brewing. I use an <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001HBCVX0?ref_=oh_aui_search_detailpage&amp;redirect=true&amp;psc=1&amp;tag=nyen0e-20" title="AeroPress">AeroPress</a> and LOVE it.  Even if you use coffee grinds from the supermarket, the Aeropress make brewing so darned easy. Both brewing and cleaning. It makes one cup at a time. Add the coffee, the water, let it sit and then pump it out. Cleaning is just popping the "puck" of spent coffee into the garbage, rinsing everything with water, and throwing it in the drainboard. I use the "inverted method" as I find it the easiest. Check out this <a href="https://bluebottlecoffee.com/frequency/aeropress-video?tonx=1" title="1 min">1 min</a> Blue Bottle video that explains it. Sometimes, I also use the <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/aeropress-timer-for-aerobies/id602496538?mt=8&amp;at=11laRZ&amp;ct=pro" title="AeroPress Timer">AeroPress Timer</a> app on my phone that, in theory, gets a better tasting brew. I stir it with the handle of the AeroPress scoop</p>

<p><img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/304/19611557190_c75f29d297_z_d.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/259/19799586545_8fa60e61ee_z_d.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Most of the time, I have the coffee exactly as it comes out of the press. This is a little closer to espresso than coffee. The instructions say "add water to taste". I've been home with <a href="https://twitter.com/timothybroder/status/617041906040762368" title="Charlie">Charlie</a> the past few weeks and have been trying this. I like both, I'm not sure which method I'll end up with. Either way, I add my 2 ice cubes</p>

<p><img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3690/19614589349_11ff2ac88c_z_d.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Now. Bulletproof Coffee. I've done this on and off over the past few years. Gizmodo <a href="http://gizmodo.com/bulletproof-coffee-debunking-the-hot-buttered-hype-1681321467" title="debunked">debunked</a> it earlier this year. What do I think? For the most part. It works. For the first few months, you feel like you've had rocket fuel and can do anything. Then, it tapers off. I do it a few times a year, usually close to the release of a website for a little boost. I eyeball a tablespoon or so of <a href="http://amzn.to/1Megeyb" title="Kerry Gold Butter">Kerry Gold Butter</a> and add a tablespoon of <a href="http://amzn.to/1fgmicy" title="MCT Oil">MCT Oil</a>. If you are going to try it, don't buy the bulletproof brand. It's not any better and amazon can save you money.</p>

<p>However you take your coffee; whether you are super fussy, love your starbucks, or dabble a little bit at home: <a href="http://www.marco.org/2014/03/31/throwing-k-cups-in-glass-houses" title="It doesn’t matter">It doesn’t matter</a>. ENJOY your coffee</p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Morning Rituals]]></title>
            <link href="https://www.timbroder.com/2014/09/morning-rituals.html"/>
            <updated>2014-09-16T15:51:28+00:00</updated>
            <id>https://www.timbroder.com/2014/09/morning-rituals.html</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Rituals are important. I’m a creature of habit. But, I had never characterized
some of the things I do as rituals.  I read some posts by <a href="http://www.caseyliss.com/2014/6/28/go-pack">Casey
Liss</a> and <a href="http://david-smith.org/blog/2014/05/22/my-travel-coffee-kit/">David Smith</a> that were not unlike
some of the things I do.  I like repetition. I like not having to think about
a decision or even make one to begin with.  Similar things for breakfast each
day. If I cook a big meal I’ll have the leftovers for subsequent meals until
they are gone.</p>

<p>Having these rituals help me get my day going. They let me know
that all is right in the world.</p>

<p>My morning ritual is something of a decision
tree:</p>

<p><strong>Gym</strong></p>

<p>I used to go to my gym a lot more often; 4-6 days a week. Adding
in runs on top of that if I was training for a race. Lately 3 days a week
seems to be my norm. I’ve grown to be ok with this. Personal and work stress
are adding up, and that’s what I can do right now. Which is funny because the
gym is a <em>huge</em> stress relief for me. But, I digress.  If I go to the gym, I
shower at the gym after my workout, then walk to work.  I either have
breakfast with me or I pick it up on the way to the office. If I have it with
me, it means I cooked it the night before: 3-4 eggs fried in coconut oil,
seasoning, maybe some sourcraut (It’s a lot better than you think it is). If I
pick it up it’s some kind of veggie omelet or scrambled eggs with a vegetable.
This has been my morning gym ritual for about 5 years now.  I started drinking
coffee about a year ago. I have a half cup from the pot of work if I eat
breakfast there.  I add 2 cubes of ice to it from work’s freezer.  I want to
drink it immediately and this brings it to the right temperature for my taste.
Having this repetition helps me start my day. I usually eat my food at the
cafe table, with my laptop, doing a quick pass of email.  I’m trying to shift
this into <em>doing</em> something with the first hour of my day, not just drowning
in email.</p>

<p>Wakeup time: 5:35am. Catch 6:07 train into the city. My clothes are
laid out the night before. Wakeup, chug protein shake so I’m not starving,
wash face, brush teeth, do inhaler, run to train.</p>

<p><strong>Home</strong></p>

<p>If I sleep in, I
eat and have coffee at home.  I’ll wakeup and jump in the shower to wake up a
little. Breakfast will be 3 eggs and sometimes a few strips of bacon.  I put
the frying pan on high. While it’s heating up I put the kettle on.  I crack a
few eggs into the pan. While they are sitting, I start getting the Aeropress
ready.  I love the Aeropress. It’s perfect for a single cup, or even 2 if I’m
making one for Laura. I get my coffee from <a href="https://tonx.org/f4a9df89">Tonx</a>.
If you aren’t familiar with them, I highly recommend. You get your coffee
every 2 weeks for a monthly fee. The beans are roasted fresh, which apparently
augments the taste.  I don’t have to worry about running out, or remembering
to pick some up from the store. It just shows up. Less stress.  The amount of
coffee I drink is perfect for their lowest plan. At most I end up with an
extra cup and a half of beans. It’s very, very rare that I run out. I also
tried Drifwaway coffee which I <strong>really</strong> liked. They send you a sample pack
of 4 types of coffee. You rate each one and this effects what your shipments
are in the future. I consistently got something I really enjoyed. I
occasionally get something I’m not a big fan of with Tonx.  You might wonder
why I don’t just pick 1 thing and stick with it. That would be less stress,
actually. But, I’m still getting into coffee and exploring what I like. I
can’t tell you right now what type of coffee I like using the right
terminology. But, Driftaway’s shipment size was too big for me, I ended up
having a decent amount leftover.</p>

<p>Wakeup time: in between 7 and 8, depending on
what my morning for work looks like</p>

<p><strong>Run</strong></p>

<p>I may, like I did this morning,
get up 30-60 mins before my sleep in time and get a run in.  If it’s going to
be raining I’ll opt for this. I love running in the rain.  The amount of
running I’ve been doing recently has dropped drastically. I’m trying to get
back into it. I really do love it. After the run, I fall into what I normally
do at home.</p>

<p>I use an alarm for all of these. For the gym, I’ll set the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Sony-Machine-Cassette-Player-Icf-cs650/dp/B00KNKJYQS?tag=nyen0e-20">Sony
clock radio</a> I’ve had since I was 6. I’m amazed it still
works, though it took me a while to find a link to it online. I wake up at the
same time for the gym, no matter the day. I just flip on the alarm. Laura
keeps it tuned to NPR, so I wake up to that.  The other days I’ll use my
phone. Siri sets alarms for whatever time I need.</p>

<p>I never snooze. Never have,
don’t think I ever will.  If I’m not going to get up until 20 mins later, I’d
rather just get that as real sleep time.  My alarm clock has always been in a
place where I have to get up to turn it off. (This was particularly helpful in
college. I woke up at 4:40 for practice. Sleep was very valuable)</p>

<p>If you are
frazzled in the morning or feel stressed out getting ready for work, think
about repetition. What would you want to do every morning? What of your
routine can be ritualized?</p>

<p>If you did a few things the night before (pick
clothes) would that lessen your stress in the morning? Think about it. I love
it. If you have any rituals that help you start your day, or lower your
stress, let me below in the comments or on</p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
    </feed>